so let's see if we know how to use
multiple predictors and combine their
decisions suppose that we have a program
in which a 2-bit predictor work just
fine for 95% of our instructions a
pshare predictor we just fine for the
same 95% of the instructions plus it
also works fine for 2% that this 2bit
predictor doesn't cover so overall it
works fine for 97% of all instructions
but the 95 % here and here overlap a
gshare predictor again works just fine
for the same 95% that all the other
predictors are just fine for plus it
works fine for the other 3% so overall
it's 98% accurate 95 of those are the
same as the 2bit predictor but the three
that it covers in addition to that are
not the same but the three that it
covers in addition to that are different
from the two % that the pshare predictor
covers so together these three
predictors should be able to correctly
predict all
instructions so the question for you is
how do we combine them so the overall
predictor that we will use is a what
kind of predictor that chooses between a
what kind of predictor and what kind of
predictor and this last predictor here
itself will choose between what kind and
what kind predictor
instead of writing in the names of the
predictors just select among the
following so for each of them say if
it's a b c d or E A is the two-bit
predictor B is the pshare predictor C is
the gshare predictor D is the tournament
predictor e is a hierarchical predictor
and F is the return address stag so
again for each of these five boxes put
which letter corresponds to the
predictor that is the right answer for
that box